

# Mehmet Akif Tütüncü

Istanbul, Turkey

♠ https://akif.dev

makiftutuncu

**in** makiftutuncu

**y** makiftutuncu

I'm a senior software engineer focused mainly on backend. I have more than 9 years of professional experience in software development. I've conducted consulting, training and worked with companies around the world such as Shazam, Socrata, Beam/MAF, sahibinden, Numbrs, Scalac and Conduktor. I am proficient in Scala, Java, Kotlin using both object-oriented and functional programming. I have skills in CI/CD, testing, databases, cloud applications, microservices. I am a fan of open-source software.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Scalac

(Nov 2021 - Present)

Numbrs

(Nov 2020 - Oct 2021)

Senior Software Engineer

I worked with Conduktor as a consultant. I migrated part of their legacy Java API to a new Scala service. It included an automated mechanism to check for correctness. I helped build user and organization management features handling multiple Conduktor products.

Software Engineer

I worked in Personal Finance Management team. I was responsible for developing new features to Numbrs app backend.

Sahibinden

(Aug 2019 - Nov 2020)

VNGRS

(May 2017 - Aug 2019)

Senior Software Engineer

I worked in the search team. The domains I usually dealt with were search, promotions and categories. I also automated the process of updating location and geo data.

Software Engineer

I consulted in multiple projects. In MAF Properties team, I worked in the kick-off process for their latest product. In Beam team, I helped migrate and maintain a mobile payment system. In Socrata team, I helped design, develop and maintain multiple backend projects.

Linovi

(Oct 2013 - Oct 2016)

iDivino

(Aug 2012 - Aug 2013)

Software Engineer

I started as a part-time here. Then joined Shazam team.
I had varying tasks from developing features, fixing bugs, writing automated tests to maintaining projects.

Android Developer

I worked part-time on developing games for preschool children.

# **PROJECTS**

e

Scala library for error handling

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/e

Scala, Kotlin, Java, circe, play-json, gson, ZIO, munit

# Muezzin

Android application and server

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/Muezzin

Scala, Java, Play Framework, PostgreSQL, Anorm, Akka

#### **Bookstore**

A project demonstrating automated testing on backend

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/bookstore

Scala, Finch, ScalaTest, Postman, Docker, Flyway, Doobie, PostgreSQL

#### k-retru

Naive retry implementation

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/k-retry

Kotlin, JUnit

## **LANGUAGES**

Turkish

Native

**English** 

Professional

# **SKILLS**

Frameworks/Libraries/Tools

Akka, AWS, cats, circe, Docker, Elasticsearch, git, Gradle, http4s, JUnit, Kafka, Play Framework, Quill, SBT, ScalaTest, Spring Framework, tapir, ZIO

**Databases** 

Cassandra, DynamoDB, Firebase, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis

**Progamming Languages** 

Go, Java, Kotlin, Scala

**Techniques** 

Agile, CI/CD, DDD, Kanban, Microservices, SCRUM, TDD

**TALKS** 

Dealing with Errors on JVM with e

ScalaUA 2020

https://youtu.be/HAQZtTZae\_Q

Kotlin for Backends

sahibinden.com D2D

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/kotlin-for-backends

Typeclass 101

VNGRS Lightning Talks

https://youtu.be/jPiM9uBHpWI

Testing Web Backends With Scala

Test Hive

https://youtu.be/QnK8pyGUOac

**ARTICLES** 

Scala Blog

(Dec 2015)

**Android Blog** 

(Jan 2012)

Wordpress

http://makiftutuncu.wordpress.com

Blogspot

http://androidce.blogspot.com

**VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE** 

Kodluyoruz

(Dec 2020 - Jan 2021) Izmir Institute of Technology

(Jan 2013 - Apr 2013)

Instructor

I gave introduction to Scala and functional programming

lectures.

Instructor

I gave Android lectures in student club at my university.

**EDUCATION** 

Izmir Institute of Technology

(Aug 2009 - Jun 2014)

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering

Education in English, focused on software, started my career halfway through with internships and part-time positions

(Jun 2020)

**CERTIFICATIONS** 

Complete Guide to Elasticsearch

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (May 2018)

Amazon

Udemy